

Walter Troiani

Computer & Data Scientist

waltertv02@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/walterjtv/

MANGO

UPC

UPC

Barcelona (Spain)

github.com/eZWALT (

walterjtv.tech



About Me

I'am a highly motivated and disciplined student, currently on the verge of completing my Computer Science degree. I've already gained valuable experience as a dedicated Data Scientist, where my passion for data has flourished. My love for learning drives me to constantly seek new challenges and knowledge, allowing me to stay at the forefront of the latest technological advancements in the field. Ready to embrace new career challenges, excel in demanding roles, and contribute effectively to hardworking teams. With a strong commitment to personal growth and driven to succeed in every endeavor.

Personal Projects

- <u>Loopback: The Game</u> (Developed in HackUPC 2022)
- <u>Falcon File Explorer</u> (Developed at college, 2023)
- <u>ASL frontend & middle-end compiler</u> (Developed at college , 2023)
- PyTorch / LLVM and more open source contributions!
 (Work in progress 2024)
- <u>Deep Learning Calorie calculator APP</u> (Work in progress 2023/24)
- MORE COMING SOON!

Certifications & Licenses

- Coaching for academic mentoring (UPC, 2021)
- Machine Learning Specialization (Coursera, 2023)
- AWS cloud practitioner (Work in progress, EDC 6/2024)
- Driving License (Work in progress, EDC 12/2023)

Languages

- Catalan(Native)
- Spanish(Native)
- English (Advanced)
- Italian (Elementary)

Work Experience

Developed data science applications following the DevOps philosophy using state-of-the-art generative-AI models and classical machine learning models in order to forecast and boost the efficiency of the supply

chain, product personalization and corporate decisions

2022- Now Buisness Fair Manager FIBVISIONA

1 year Coordinated and managed the FibVisiona Forum, a job fair hosting cutting-edge tech companies. Led advertising, planning, and execution,

fostering valuable connections with industry leaders.

2021- 2023 Undergraduate Professor

2 years Experienced hardware educator at the Aula Lliure project at FIB-UPC.

Guided and inspired absolute beginners, nurturing their curiosity and

passion for technology's building blocks

2019 - 2022 Butcher's Shop Assistant ARNALL

3 years Butcher's Shop Assistant ensuring top-notch customer satisfaction through personalized service.

Education

2020-2024 Computer Science and Engineering

(EAC) Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (Barcelona)

2018-2020 Technological Baccalaureate Sant Gabriel

Graduated with high honors, Col·legi Sant Gabriel (Girona)

Skills & Tools

- Discipline, perspective, empathy, love for learning, and honesty define my signature traits. Moreover, my exceptional problem-solving skills, abstraction, and critical thinking shape the essence of who I am.
- I love working in teams and enjoy taking the lead when the things get stuck or the chance arises. My
 gentle, outgoing and adaptable nature helps me connect with others effortlessly.
- Proficiency in C/C++/Java/Python/Kotlin
- Familiar with languages such as Haskell/Prolog/Javascript/R/Scala
- Comfortable in front-end using HTML/CSS, Streamlit, REST API's & HTTP
- Experience with assembly languages such as MIPS/x86/ARM and linux environments
- Experienced in C++ libraries such as OpenGL, CUDA, OMP, ANTLR, LLVM
- Familiar with the postgreSQL language and using MongoDB, S3, DynamoDB, snowflake databases
- Experience developing applications using Infrastructure As Code (IAC) with Terraform/Terragrunt in AWS environment's
- Used to distributed computing with AWS in a wide range of services: DynamoDB, EC2, S3, ECS and a fair amount of experience with Apache PySpark
- Developer experienced in DevOps methodology and CI/CD using technologies as: Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Jira, Confluence, BitBucket, Git (In General) and Airflow
- Self-taught data scientist, comfortable on Jupyter/DataBricks/Colab notebook environments and experienced in diverse libraries such as Pandas, PySpark, Plotly...
- Hands-on experience in developing projects and applications using machine learning algorithms, some developed with pytorch, tensorflow, scikit-learn, LightGBM, XGBoost, Prophet, LLama2 and other pre-trained generative AI popular models
- Lifelong learner, always curious and learning about a wide range of different topics such as computer science, data science, AI, cloud computing, algorithmic trading, mathematics and physics on my leisure time

More about me on my personal website walterjtv.tech!